What are you doing now with the with the
eye stuff?
>> Well, I mean, I'm more curious to hear
your thoughts and predictions, frankly,
because I think you're better at it, but
I mean, I'm using
Claude code with Ferris APIs to do tons
of like inbox analysis and stuff.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> Right? I'm doing a 20-year
retrospective analysis of angel
investing.
>> Mhm.
>> It's like, who made what introductions?
Which companies did I not reply to that
ended up being successes? Which did I
turn down that ended up being
really important.
>> really want to do that to yourself?
>> Well, I suspected it'd be worse than it
was. I actually have not I haven't
missed that many explicit opportunities.
I wanted to test my own stories against
data, right? Cuz I have all sorts of
stories
>> Right.
>> about why I did certain things and why
certain things worked out. And I have
certain stories about my
batting average. And I'm like,
but is it true?
>> Right.
>> Really?
>> Is it really true?
>> Let's look at some hard numbers.
>> The sad truth, and I have a buddy that
wears that the bracelet and you've seen
me with the necklace around that we
categorizes your AI and listens to you
24/7.
>> Yeah.
>> It's about 70-ish percent that we think
we know, but is actually what we know.
>> Yeah.
>> Out of the 100% of like what we think we
know, this is the truth. I said I wanted
a dark chocolate bar at 7:00 p.m.
>> Yeah.
>> It's like, no, you said it at 5:00 and
you said it this way.
>> And you said it was milk chocolate.
>> Yeah, exactly. So, it's always about 20%
off from where you actually think your
brain's at. Sure.
>> Which is brutal.
>> Well, plus, I mean, that's like last
week, right? If you're talking about 15
years ago.
>> I mean, if you listen to any genesis
story of any startup, you're like,
>> Oh my god.
>> Wait a minute now. Like, this is like a
startup comic working on material, but
he's been working on this one 5-minute
bit so long that now he believes that's
actually truth.
>> Yeah.
>> That I mean, the sanitizing and the
editing of these startup genesis stories
is hilarious, and there's no reason to
think that I would be or you would be
exempt from it.
>> Right.
>> Right, when you're telling your own
story, even if you're just telling it to
yourself.
>> So, what's the number one thing that
you've learned by applying AI to your
life in this fashion? Like, what's the
thing where you walked away and said
"Damn, that was insightful, and I'm
going to change my behavior, or I
learned something new about myself that
I wouldn't have if if I had not used
AI."
>> Well, I think from a holistic health
perspective, by holistic I mean
having enough data related to
medications, supplements,
predispositions, side effects, what
happened to me 2 weeks ago,
the LLMs have been incredibly helpful. I
mean, the picture that they get and the
speed with which they can deliver an
answer that I can interrogate is just
incredible.
>> What did you learn? Like, what was the
thing that you
>> I mean, honestly, it's mostly avoiding
disaster, right? It's like, are any of
these things contraindicated with one
another?
>> Could A, B, or C explain D?
>> And you have to keep in mind, these
things can still hallucinate, but
you can
I don't want to say eliminate that, but
minimize it by just fact-checking across
LLMs. There's that. I would say that
there's a lot of insight on, hopefully,
that that can translate to future
decision-making related to
investing, which investing for me is not
just amassing more chips. What's fun
about investing to me is it's a way to
scorecard your thinking and
decision-making.
It's just a very objective way
to decide if something was the right or
the wrong decision. And you can
fine-slice that, and there are ways that
you could maybe question that, but
if you're asking yourself, "Was I
thinking well last month?" That's not a
very helpful question. Where do you go
from there?
If you're logging maybe every decision
you make every day and then trying to
cross-reference outcomes with blah blah
blah. Like, yeah, but you're never going
to do that.
>> Mhm.
>> But when you're making relatively
frequent investments, you can do that.
You can also run counterfactuals, right?
What if I did the opposite? What if I
had not sold that? What if I had kept
that? What if I had done this? What if I
had done that?
>> Is that worth your time though? At the
end of the day, you could put everything
in the S&P 500 and just go to bed.
>> Well, there's that. I would say it's
worth it to me because I find it
interesting.
I actually enjoy the intellectual
exercise of it. But otherwise, I would
say with
in terms of like how AI has has impacted
me,
I would say that
the honest answer is not that much
because most [__] isn't worth doing in
the first place. People are finding
very, very clever ways to expedite
automating workflows of all different
types and doing something well does not
make it important or worth doing in the
first place. So, there's a lot I think
the level of [__] that is being done
just at a very fast, efficient rate is
skyrocketing. Yeah. But simultaneously,
there are definitely cases where
I look back at say this analysis of 20
years of stuff.
To do that manually would be impossible.
>> Sure.
>> All right, it would take me a year
full-time with multiple people to do
that. And with a Claude code Gmail API
and
leaving my computer running for a
handful of hours a few times, it's like,
what you get back is [__] credible.
>> Yeah.
>> Like, it's unbelievable. And I haven't
even scratched the surface.
>> Yeah.
>> I will say also another way that AI has
maybe affected my life in a
net negative way, and I'm not We have
another mutual friend who maybe we
shouldn't name who feels very similarly
is
We'll leave that out, but yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> Jesus Christ. So, if you train
AIs on your writing,
they're really good.
>> Yeah.
>> And I think I feel This is a stretch of
a comparison, obviously, cuz I'm not
an adept like a world-class Go player,
but when AlphaGo defeated one of the top
Korean players,
>> Mhm.
>> he was kind of like, "I'm done. Like, I
don't find joy in this anymore."
>> Yeah.
>> If we're playing against machines.
>> And when I see these AIs very
beautifully, I'm not going to lie.
And they're We're like in the top of the
first inning, right? This stuff is going
to get so much better. Spit out stuff
that is so much better.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, I can still write, but what they
can do in 30 seconds is what would take
me 30 hours. And I'm just like, "Fuck."
It really drains the motivation for me
to put in those 30 hours.
>> Yeah.
>> Why wouldn't it? Of course it would,
right?
>> Yeah, but in some sense, you can
consider it a really good co-pilot
because for it to come up with novel
ideas that would engage an audience,
that's still the holy grail where it's
not quite there yet, right? Like, it's
going to make you sound It's going to
button up your copy.
And it might expand upon it in ways that
you wouldn't. But it's not going to come
up with the original thesis for the
whole thing, right?
>> Yeah, it's going to have trouble with
the original thesis, but even there,
I think it does a pretty good job.
>> Really? It's getting better. I haven't
tried with writing stuff.
>> do a data dump and you're like,
"Create."
>> Oh, oh, you sent me that link.
>> Yeah, if you just do a data dump and
you're like, "Create."
>> Where you sent me that link, you were
like, "What should Tim do in the next 5
years?"
>> Oh, yeah, that was good.
>> really interesting. Tell people what you
did because like they might find this
They could apply this to their own life.
>> Sure. So, you could do this in whichever
model you're using, whether it's, you
know, Claude or ChatGPT or whatever.
If it knows you,
>> you can tie in your inbox, too.
>> Yeah, you can tie in your inbox. In my
case, I didn't do that, but if it has
enough history on you, you can just ask,
"What do you think I should do in the
next 5 years? What might be
some rewarding paths of exploration?" I
think I put something like that. "What
are three to five ideas
that you think could be rewarding career
exploration for me in the next X period
of time?"
>> So, for people listening, if they've
used AI for, let's call it, 3 to 6
months, and you've probably given it
several hundred things to think about,
yeah, it will span across those
conversations, as long as you turn this
on. It's I think it's on by default now,
but it used to be an opt-in thing, where
you have to say, "Allow the AI to look
cross-conversation." So, it has a
holistic understanding of who you are.
>> And the answers were [__]
outstanding.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, really, really good.
>> And I sent it to a few friends, sent to
you, I sent it to a few of my closest
friends, and they're like, "That's
pretty [__] good."
>> Yeah.
>> I mean,
>> It was really cool. Some of the ideas I
was like, "Damn, you should do that,
dude."
>> Yeah.
>> It had this one business idea for you to
do, and it wasn't a book.
>> Yeah.
>> And I was like, "Dude, I texted you
back. I was like, that's awesome. Like,
go go build that."
>> Yeah. There were business ideas, there
were certainly kind of non-revenue,
but philosophically aligned ideas. It
was shocking to me. So, that's actually
a very good example of something that
has deeply informed what I'm mulling
over. As I imagine the future, I was
like, "Man, that actually is a really
good." Because, keeping in mind, I'm
asking questions about
things of interest, things I like,
things I don't like. I am asking
questions about
different scientific interests related
to Sci Sci Foundation, my nonprofit
foundation. I'm asking questions about
investing. I'm asking questions about
writing. I'm asking questions about
relationships. I'm asking questions
about organizing trips for friends. I'm
asking so many different questions. I
>> on the board of your nonprofit? I think
you're like secretary or something.
>> Yeah, something like that. [laughter]
>> I've never heard anything about that.
>> Yeah, I don't know. Maybe you were
honorably discharged. I don't know.
>> I did. [laughter] I never got any
paperwork around it. I've never heard
anything in like 3 years. I'm like,
okay.
>> Yeah, well, I said it was going to be a
light lift. It's a light lift.
>> It's a light lift.
>> [laughter]
[snorts]
>> That's a very good example, right? I
mean, that's that may be the best
example because if that even 10% informs
like a major next chapter.
>> Yeah.
>> 100%.
>> Like that's a big deal for me,
certainly.
And it makes me think a little bit about
podcast listeners, especially. Readers
also, but to a greater extent podcast
listeners who come up to me
and most most listeners I run into are
really great. And not I mean, there are
always a couple of weirdos, but most are
fantastic and they'll say something
often like, "I'm so sorry, you don't
know me at all and I feel like I know
you." And what I say a lot of the time
is actually, "If you listen to my
podcasts every week or even every month,
you do know me pretty well."
>> Yeah.
>> And then you think about
a machine that never forgets.
>> Yeah.
>> It's going to know you pretty damn well.
>> of course.
>> And it's spooky in a way.
>> Yeah.
>> But I started getting more out of the
LLMs
when I started asking questions and I
have to be I think a little careful with
outsourcing this
and absolving yourself of responsibility
to think about these things, but when
you ask it open-ended personal questions
in the way that you would ask a close
friend,
>> Mhm.
>> what do you think are three to five
creative ways I might explore things
professionally in the next 5 years?
>> Yeah.
>> As opposed to something that you think
is more suitable for a robot.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> You get some really interesting
responses.
>> That's a great use case.